<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2026 Mikhail Gavrilov -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.ntman.PerDeviceEQ</id>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <name>Per-Device EQ</name>
  <summary>Per-output-device parametric EQ for PipeWire</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      Per-Device EQ applies a parametric equaliser directly inside the real
      PipeWire sink, so every output device — speakers, a Bluetooth headset,
      a USB DAC — keeps its own correction. The EQ is written as an in-node
      filter graph, with no extra virtual sink in the audio path, and is
      restored automatically by a WirePlumber hook: it survives reboot and
      device reconnect with no background process of your own running.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>One saved correction per output device, applied and restored automatically</li>
      <li>Interactive editor with a frequency-response graph, per-channel bands and a preamp</li>
      <li>Import REW and AutoEQ filters; export and reuse profiles</li>
      <li>Applies to every application, including pro-audio tools that open the device directly</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.ntman.PerDeviceEQ.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/NTMan/PerDeviceEQ</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/NTMan/PerDeviceEQ/issues</url>

  <developer id="io.github.ntman">
    <name>Mikhail Gavrilov</name>
  </developer>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Editing the equaliser for a Bluetooth headset</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/NTMan/PerDeviceEQ/main/per-device-eq-screenshot.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <categories>
    <category>AudioVideo</category>
    <category>Audio</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>equalizer</keyword>
    <keyword>EQ</keyword>
    <keyword>PipeWire</keyword>
    <keyword>parametric</keyword>
    <keyword>AutoEQ</keyword>
    <keyword>REW</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>

  <releases>
    <release version="4.0.1" date="2026-07-24">
      <description>
        <p>Packaging release: AppImage for non-Fedora distros joins every release</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.0.0" date="2026-07-23">
      <description>
        <p>Measurement schema v4: per-take calibration passports, and the app arrives as a Flatpak</p>
        <p>Every take now carries its own calibration -- rig stamps
        live on sessions, calibration curves in an append-only
        library -- so the statistics judge calibrated curves and
        recorded calibrations can be reassigned in bulk. Existing
        profiles convert once with the bundled migration tool.</p>
        <p>The Flatpak ships scoped permissions, full PipeWire
        control from inside the sandbox, and a system-integration
        switch in the main menu: one-click install and removal,
        with a copyable restart command.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.2.0" date="2026-07-22">
      <description>
        <p>Add export to external PEQ/GEQ</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.0" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <p>The app is the instrument now: built-in sweep measurement
        with incremental takes and automatic fitting, a taste layer
        composed over any profile on any device, honest headroom, and
        an adaptive measurement window.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2026-06-30"/>
  </releases>
</component>
